

Patrick Dwyer

Data Scientist at Manifold Group with 1+ years of software development experience. Experience in Software Development, Computer Vision, Time Series Modeling/Forecasting, and DevOps. Strong knowledge of Python, Javascript, and SQL. Interested in building software that improves the world at least a little bit. Based in Saint Louis but open to hybrid positions.

Experience

Manifold Group: Data Scientist

- Built CI pipeline for building and publishing back end machine learning and database management services as Docker containers to AWS ECR with GitLab
- Building database management and machine learning backend services in Python and Node.js as Dockerized applications

Websanity: Web Developer

• Freelance Web Developer for Rulepop, an emerging rules reference platform for tabletop games

October 2023 - Present

- Defined postgres database schema in relation to machine learning model requirements and existing data pipeline constraints
- Developing real-time (<30 second response latency) streamed anomoly detection/forcasting models on time series data

September 2023 - October 2023

 Implemented search using Fuse.js, page sharing using share api and dynamic title switching for all live rules references

Schwartz Lab: Lab Tech

- Developed supervised 3d Convolutional Neural Network in
 PyTorch
- Set up extrinsic camera calibration routine by implementing •
 Levenberg-Marquardt for Bundle Adjustment
- Extended PyTorch torch.autograd.Function class to integrate 3d→2d point projection into autograd
 - Manually labelled 8,544 ground truth 2d points using selfmade image labeling program

Manifold Group: Data Science Intern

July 2022 - March 2023

July 2023 - Sep 2023

- Collaborated with head of data analytics to build a modular and extendable data pipeline in Python using Pandas and NumPy
- Visualized data for head of data analytics and partners using Matplotlib and Altair

Technical Skills

Languages Tools Libraries

Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS, SCSS, HTML, Bash(Unix shell)

Docker, ECR, Postgres (RDS), Node.js, npm, git, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Tower, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter node:http, node:fs, Fuse.js, NumPy, PyTorch, Matplotlib, Pandas, OpenCV, Flask

Education

BA: Mathematics, Computer Science

Sep 2019 - June 2023

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL — Weinberg College of Arts and Sciences — 3.43/4.00 GPA

Projects

patrickdwyer.com Summer 2023-Present

Responsive CV website built from scratch using no pre-built libraries and industry best practices